[
  {
    "id": 1,
    "question": "Which year did the construction of the Alhambra begin?",
    "alternatives": {
      "1": "1238",
      "2": "1492",
      "3": "711",
      "4": "1066"
    },
    "correctAnswer": "1"
  },
  {
    "id": 2,
    "question": "What is the name of the famous mosque in Cordoba?",
    "alternatives": {
      "1": "Hagia Sophia",
      "2": "Mezquita",
      "3": "Al-Aqsa",
      "4": "Blue Mosque"
    },
    "correctAnswer": "2"
  },
  {
    "id": 3,
    "question": "Who was the last ruler of Granada?",
    "correctAnswer": "boabdil"
  },
  {
    "id": 4,
    "question": "Al-Zahrawi (Abulcasis) is famous for his pioneering work in which field?",
    "alternatives": {
      "1": "Surgery",
      "2": "Poetry",
      "3": "Architecture",
      "4": "Programmer"
    },
    "correctAnswer": "1"
  },
  {
    "id": 5,
    "question": "Which city was the capital of the Caliphate?",
    "alternatives": {
      "1": "Seville",
      "2": "Toledo",
      "3": "Cordoba",
      "4": "Valencia"
    },
    "correctAnswer": "3"
  },
  {
    "id": 6,
    "question": "True or False: The Giralda was originally a minaret.",
    "alternatives": {
      "1": "True",
      "2": "False"
    },
    "correctAnswer": "1"
  },
  {
    "id": 7,
    "question": "Who is credited with the first scientific attempt at flight in Cordoba?",
    "alternatives": {
      "1": "Ibn Battuta",
      "2": "Abbas ibn Firnas",
      "3": "Al-Idrisi",
      "4": "Sinan"
    },
    "correctAnswer": "2"
  },
  {
    "id": 8,
    "question": "Which polymath introduced the 3-course meal, crystal glasses, and seasonal fashion to Cordoba?",
    "alternatives": {
      "1": "Al-Khwarizmi",
      "2": "Boabdil",
      "3": "Zryab",
      "4": "Tariq ibn Ziyad"
    },
    "correctAnswer": "3"
  },
  {
    "id": 9,
    "question": "How long did the Al-Andalus Emirate last?",
    "correctAnswer": "800 years"
  },
  {
    "id": 10,
    "question": "Ibn Rushd was a famous philosopher from Cordoba. What is his Westernized name?",
    "correctAnswer": "averroes"
  },
  {
    "id": 11,
    "question": "The 'Noria', widely used in Al-Andalus agriculture, is a type of what?",
    "alternatives": {
      "1": "Sword",
      "2": "Musical instrument",
      "3": "Spice",
      "4": "Water wheel"
    },
    "correctAnswer": "4"
  },
  {
    "id": 12,
    "question": "Where does Al-Andalus locate geographically?",
    "alternatives": {
      "1": "Morocco",
      "2": "Spain",
      "3": "Mexico",
      "4": "Dagestan"
    },
    "correctAnswer": "2"
  }
]